Martijn van Halen

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mvanhalen/

https://mvanhalen.eu

Spain Almeria

English | Dutch | Spanish

Summary

I am a full-stack engineer and technical founder with over 20 years of experience in fintech, mobile apps, cloud computing, and crypto/Web3. I have built products and services from the ground up, creating viable businesses that scaled to acquisitions (e.g., Payvision, sold for \$200M) and startups that secured venture capital. My expertise spans developing minimum viable products, achieving product-market fit, and driving growth to millions of users, subscriptions, and transactions.

Skills

- Entrepreneurial drive: Transforming ideas into Minimum Viable Products, achieving Product-Market Fit, and scaling beyond—raising \$500K+, building multimillion-dollar companies, and growing user bases to millions.
- Full-stack execution: Delivering end-to-end solutions from mobile apps to cloud infrastructure.
- Engineering excellence: Consistently succeeding in technical projects and challenges across 20+ years.
- CTO & Architect expertise: Leading technical strategy and engaging with suppliers, customers, investors, and boards.
- Al-enhanced productivity: Leveraging Al tools to boost efficiency tenfold (10X).

Technical skills

Programming: JavaScript / Typescript, Svelte, React, C#, Dart (Flutter), Go, SQL, Graph Ql, Solidity and more

Frameworks: SvelteKit, Angular, Vue, Next.js, Bootstrap, Flutter and more

DevOps/Cloud: Azure, Google, Cloudflare, Vercel, Big Query, GitHub, Docker, Redis, RabbitMQ, ETH scaffold, Hardhat, Chai and more

Crypto: Blockchains (DeSo, Ethereum, Polygon), EVM Smart Contracts (Solidity), Web3, SocialFi, Lens Protocol, WalletConnect, Alchemy, Infura and more

Social web 3 Marketplaces for NFTz / InterSocial

As co-founder and CTO / full stack developer worked on Social NFT marketplaces and a Mobile app. Raised \$500K from DeSo and various grants from Lens Protocol. This resulted in https://nftz.me and https://orna.art multi chain products which bought are flagships for the blockchain or protocol they are active in. Created and developed the services from scratch. InterSocial app is the mobile app for iOS and Android which you can download here https://intersocial.xyz/getapp

Mobile app generator SaaS for iGenApps

As co-founder and CTO set up the backend and mobile web app generator from scratch resulting in a viable business that could sustain itself. The backend was used by a Mobile App which allowed people to create their mobile app via a mobile app. Has millions of registered users and thousands of active users via a subscription model. Also generated a native preview via a dev ops pipeline building an app and compiling it to an IPA and APK for Apple and Android

Fintech services for Payvision

As co-founder and CTO set up the Fintech company from 3 people myself included to a 25-person business when I exited successfully. Later it was bought by ING for over \$200 million. Payvision was innovative in payment processing for credit cards and media solutions for Video on Demand, Music on Deman and Games on Demand.

Guided and set up a 10-person tech team of engineers and developers. Later expanding to satellite office in Spain. Responsible for all tech.

Experience

NFTz INC

CTO, full stack developer and co-founder - December 2021 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Social marketplaces for web 3. Flag ship apps on the specific blockchain and protocol.

Responsibilities:

- I am responsible for all technical things running the platform and setting it up.
- We raised \$500K in 2021 to build it out and raised over \$50K from the community
- We set up payrolling and bank / crypto finances (NFTzToken)
- I created https://nftz.me for DeSo
- I created https://orna.art for Lens Protocol
- I created InterSocial mobile app https://intersocial.xyz/getapp
- I set up a data flow for Orna based on BigQuery from Google
- I set up several contracts on Polygon for auction and tipping on Lens
- I created InterSocial mobile app (pending release).
- Introduced 3D NFTs and 3D (Three.js) galleries with mini games

- I worked with SvelteKit, Azure, BigQuery, Vercel, Graph QL, ETH scaffold (Hardhat and Solidity) and Flutter.
- Active on various blockchains like DeSo, but Orna is multichain (Polygon, Ethereum, Zora, Optimism, Arbitrum and Base)
- Setup indexers for Polygon chain for certain contract events
- Setup a DeSo firehose with Go and RabbitMQ for incoming transactions
- Created Audio Spaces for NFTz users to connect via audio in real time. Flutter and Web

iGenApps INC

CTO, full stack developer and co-founder - December 2013 - January 2022 (8 years 2 months)

Mobile app generator SaaS. Create mobile apps with your mobile

Responsibilities:

- I was responsible for all technical things running the platform and setting it up.
- I set up the compete backend and mobile app generating service
- Created instant mobile app PWA with services workers
- Integrated and setup subscription flow with Apple, Google and Stripe
- Added a native mobile app preview for subscribers. Android APK and iOS IPA
- Scaled the app to millions of registered users and thousands of active users
- I worked with Used Azure, Svelte, Flutter, Firebase and Stripe

Equens SE

System Engineer and Architect - April 2009 - October 2010 (1 year 7 months)

Biggest payment provider in the Netherlands

Responsibilities:

 Worked with the engineering team and architects to maintain and improve the payment architecture

Payvision

CTO and co-founder - April 2002 - March 209 (7 years)

Cards payment provider

Responsibilities:

- Set up technical services for company from scratch
- Create 10-person tech team
- Open satellite office in Madrid
- Scaled to successful Fintech company and exited
- Setup checkout and Media services for Media on demand

Projects as Self Employed:

Created an Al rooms service with Next.js and React using OpenAl Embeddings

Lens Frame Polygon contract for Galverse

• A pet Lens Frame to feed, clean and play with a virtual pet. Also did the Solidity contract

Payrolling platform for We Pay People

• Migrate and develop an existing Payrolling system to Azure cloud.

Mobile apps and content management systems for Kystcentret

• Mobile apps for android, windows and apple with a shared content management system in azure cloud for Danish Kystcentret amusement park

Earlier in career

Various System Engineering and developer roles in The Netherlands

Education

Hogeschool van Amsterdam

HBO, Business Computer Science · (1998 – 1999, aborted for job in IT)

Hobbies/Languages/Other

Love reading Sci Fi, my family and speak Dutch, English and Spanish